(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T21:51:36.229928",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Welcome to Chromatic Future.
身も心も
Body and soul...
この手で Make you mine
With these hands, I'll make you mine
Oh baby I need you I need you ずっと
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever
君を見る度に
Every time I look at you
上書きされてく欲望に
Overwritten by overwhelming desire
重なる Eyes, Eyes, Eyes
Meeting our Eyes, Eyes, Eyes
見せて Smile, Smile, Smile
Show me a Smile, Smile, Smile
ねえ その姿形
Hey, your figure, your form...
全てが白く霞んでいく
Everything fades into a white haze
恋から 愛、愛、愛
From crush to Love, Love, Love
毎秒 眩しくなっていく
Growing brighter with every passing second
手を伸ばせばもう届く距離
Close enough to reach if I extend my hand
Hey can I? 試したい
Hey, can I? I want to try
穏やかに 恋したい
I want to fall in love peacefully
どんなシーンも 私に見せて
Show me every single scene
このまま Stay by my side
Just stay by my side like this
どこにも行かないで
Don't go anywhere else
100% 完璧な
Because it's a 100% perfect...
純粋な愛だから
...and pure kind of love
抑えきれない感情
These uncontrollable feelings...
その手で抱きしめてよ
...hold them tight with your hands
ずっとここからさぁ
From here on out, come on
ずっともっと近くで
Much, much closer
見つめ合えたら
If we can lock eyes
溢れるほどの 持て余す 泣き濡らす Like
Overflowing, uncontrollable, tear-stained like...
Hey, tell me what's wrong with me
何も問題ないはずだし
Nothing should be wrong, after all
君の全部知りたい
I want to know everything about you
Are you needing master?
最初は声かけるだけで良かった
At first, just talking to you was enough
だけど次第に我が儘になった
But gradually, I became selfish
誰かに笑いかけ その仕草にイラ立ち
Smiling at someone else, irritated by that gesture...
隠せない自分に気づいた
...I realized I couldn't hide my true feelings
独り占めしたい
I want you all to myself
いっそ鎖に繋いで
I'd rather tie you up in chains
二人きりの部屋 近距離
A room just for the two of us, so close
願望を発現化したい
I want to bring my desires to life
甘い声で眠りたい
I want to sleep to your sweet voice
君の吐息感じさせて
Let me feel your breathing
Forever stay by your side
どこにも行かせない
I won't let you go anywhere
100% 私だけに依存してね いいでしょ？
Depend 100% only on me, okay? Is that fine?
強まる愛憎 丸ごと受け止めてよ
Accept all of this growing love and hate
私なしだとしても息ができない くらいに壊して
Break me to the point where I can't even breathe without you
あふれる情動
Overflowing emotions
もう止められない 絶対
Absolutely impossible to stop now
Hey, tell me what's wrong with me
何も問題ないはずだし
Nothing should be wrong, after all
君の全部知りたい
I want to know everything about you
I do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now
目を閉じたら 止め処ない愛が
If I close my eyes, this endless love...
触れたいよ
...makes me want to touch you
私の歌声だけ
Only my singing voice...
このまま Stay by my side
Just stay by my side like this
二度と離れないで
Don't ever leave me again
100% 純粋な愛だから
Because it's a 100% pure love
命令？ 抑えられない感情
Orders? Feelings I can't suppress
衝動で出た 示したいよ
Driven by impulse, I want to show you
ああ ここから輝く
Ah, shining from right here
ずっともっと近くで 認め合いたい
Wanting to acknowledge each other much closer
あからさまな衝動
An obvious impulse
甘そうだから ノックアウト
Looks sweet, so it's a knockout
Tell me what's wrong with me
ナンモナイナイ ぶち壊し
Nothing at all, tearing it down
ナイナイ 意味の全部知りたい
Wanting to know the full meaning of nothingness
I do need you 今すぐ
I do need you right now
Oh baby, I need you, I need you ずっと
Oh baby, I need you, I need you forever
逃げるなら今だけよ 勝利を願っちゃって
If you're going to run, now's your only chance; wish for victory
ハメ外して
Letting loose
This is OUR WAR!
不都合すぎてごめんね？
Sorry for being so inconvenient, okay?
Are you ready? もしチェッカーのサイン
Are you ready? If that's the checker's sign
揺れない 揺れぬ If then else...
Unwavering, unshakeable, If then else...
見失った 走る先に ほら 誰か
Lost sight of them—look, someone is up ahead running
Just stay scanning
アナログでは Standby now
In analog mode, standby now
もう正直 飽き飽きなのよ
Honestly, I'm already sick and tired of this
トラウマ感触 わたしには未知の味ね
Traumatic sensation—it's an unknown flavor to me
RAM 22 に挑戦的 メディックの山と P20
Defiant with RAM 22, a pile of med kits and a P20
All good try! 居直る行為 なんかやり直して
All good try! Redo that defiant attitude or something
写真じゃない？ 自分らしく
Isn't it like a photo? Being true to myself
Day by day 主張しあって
Day by day, asserting ourselves to each other
言ったこと全部ピンを刺した
I pinged everything I said
笑ってくれたっていいさ
It's fine if you laugh at me
見破れない 暗夜は怖すぎて
Unable to see through it, the dark night is too scary
Victory to 1st place!
手に入れた場所と覚悟はきっと 陰りないはずよ
The spot we gained and our resolve surely won't fade
見てみてよ この今日 強く強くいらっしゃって
Look at today, standing strong and powerful
黄色い悲鳴 戯言
Cheering screams, nonsense
雑音 わたしを強くしていくわ
Noise makes me stronger
反省射撃の射撃から 覗かれるのは尺ね
Being peeked at while firing back is annoying
脳神経系に 1 2 3
Into the central nervous system, 1 2 3
死ぬのは嫌で Trip trip
Hating to die, trip trip
気がついたら Long 3 day
Before I knew it, long 3 days
あれれ 隠れていただけ
Oh my, I was just hiding
ナイナイナイな ファイティング 構えない
No-no-no fighting, unable to get ready
泣いちゃって やめないさ これが私のキャパになる
Crying, but I won't stop—this expands my capacity
Victory to 1st place!
共に進む 叩きたいな 熱き血の真ん中を
Moving forward together, wanting to strike at the center of hot blood
ここ 地域の今日の今日 君染まっちゃって
Here today, you're fully immersed in it
紙吹雪 太陽に威張る
Confetti boasting to the sun
BPM 増したって
Even if the BPM increases
Hey I am ぶれないで
Hey I am, don't falter
Day by day もぐって まだまだ
Day by day diving in, still not done
降り立つ地に アカウント取って
Taking an account on the land we land on
笑ってくれたって
Even if you laugh at us
言っちゃったらみんな いつかチャンピオンと呼ぶはずだけ
Say it out loud, everyone will surely call us champions someday
Victory to 1st place!
風を抜く 夕暮れの光で 行動を
Taking action in the light of dusk cutting through the wind
忘れられないほどの
So much that it can't be forgotten
勝利を願っちゃって
Wishing for victory
意地を行こう同士
Let's hold our ground together, comrades
Siapa di sini yang lelah dengan kehidupan?
Who here is tired of life?
Aku!
Me!
Kalau capek, enaknya gimana nih, HoloHero?
When you're tired, what's the best thing to do, HoloHero?
Dah lah saja...
Just let it be...
CAKEEEP!
Nice!
saat dunia tak berjalan semestinya (oh, oh)
When the world doesn't go as it should (oh, oh)
mungkin sudahlah saatnya
Maybe now is the time
kau coba lepaskan saja
to just try and let it go.
tak perlu tanya mengapa lagi
No need to ask why anymore.
jika memang...
If indeed...
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
you don't get an answer,
jangan tangisi, coba lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to solve its riddle.
relakanlah
Let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
because in the end,
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you are stronger than you think.
dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just forget about it, oh, just forget about it.
jalani saja
Just live through it.
dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just forget about it, oh, just forget about it.
jalani saja
Just live through it.
walau kadang mati rasa
Even if you sometimes feel numb,
bahkan hingga tak berdaya
or even completely helpless,
dan usahamu terasa sia-sia
and your efforts feel in vain.
jika memang...
If indeed...
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
you don't get an answer,
jangan tangisi, coba lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to solve its riddle.
relakanlah
Let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
because in the end,
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you are stronger than you think.
lepas semua kendali
Let go of all control,
tancap gas dan berlari
step on the gas and run,
terima dan sudahi
accept it and put an end to it.
jika memang...
If indeed...
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
you don't get an answer,
jangan tangisi, coba lalui teka-tekinya
don't cry over it, try to solve its riddle.
relakanlah
Let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
because in the end,
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you are stronger than you think.
You are stronger than you think.
dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just forget about it, oh, just forget about it.
jalani saja
Just live through it.
dahlah saja, oh dahlah saja
Just forget about it, oh, just forget about it.
jalani saja
Just live through it.
maa ii ka
Oh well, whatever.
Halo Comic Frontier! Selamat malam!
Hello Comic Frontier! Good evening!
Welcome to hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future!
Gila, gila, gila!
Crazy, crazy, crazy!
Makasih banyak semuanya udah pada dateng ke konser 5 tahun kita ya!
Thank you so much everyone for coming to our 5th anniversary concert!
Wah, gak berasa gak sih udah 5 tahun aja?
Wow, doesn't it feel like 5 years went by so fast?
Kalau gitu, kita mulai dari perkenalan diri dulu gak sih? Mulai dari aku, aku!
If so, should we start with introductions first? Starting with me, me!
Oke, oke, ehem ehem ehem... Uh di belakang? Oke.
Okay, okay, ahem ahem... Uh, behind? Okay.
A-a-a, mission start!
Start! Aku Vestia Zeta dari hololive Indonesia gen 3, nice to meet you!
Start! I am Vestia Zeta from hololive Indonesia Gen 3, nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you too, Zeta! Iya, iya, iya, iya!
Nice to meet you too, Zeta! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Oke, next Kaela!
Okay, next Kaela!
Kaelo, grinding every time, the blacksmith from hololive ID gen 3! I'm Kaela Kovalskia, nice to meet you all!
Nice to meet you Kaelo!
Next, next, next, Kobo, Kobo, Kobo!
Hai! Boco-boco Kobo Kanaeru at your service! Let me be your sun to shine your day! Ehe!
Hi! Boco-boco Kobo Kanaeru at your service! Let me be your sun to shine your day! Ehe!
Kobokers, mana suaranya?!
Kobokers, make some noise!
Nah bertiga kami dari hololive Indonesia gen 3, holoh3ro!
The three of us are from hololive Indonesia Gen 3, holoh3ro!
Gak nyangka juga deh, konser 5th Anniversary hololive ID ini akhirnya ada juga!
I really didn't expect this hololive ID 5th Anniversary concert to finally happen!
Dari lagu pertama aja udah keren banget, guys! Kerasa gak sih?!
Just from the first song, it's already so cool, guys! Can you feel it?!
一曲目からもうめっちゃかっこいいよね！その熱き、感じてるわ！わ！
From the very first song, it's so cool! I can really feel that heat!
やばいっすね
It's insane.
アドレナリンがわいてくるんだもん これ走りたくなるっすね
Adrenaline is pumping! It makes me want to start running.
おいおいおい どこ行くの？
Hey, hey, hey, where are you going?
いやいやストップストップ！
No, no, stop, stop!
汗かくんよ！汗！
You're gonna sweat! Sweat!
カエラはどう？
How about you, Kaela?
わあ、すごく楽しい まさか自分がここに立てるとは思わなかったよ
Wow, it's so much fun! I never thought I'd be standing here.
でもちなみにライブはまだまだ長いから 最後まで張り切っていこうね！
But by the way, the concert is still long, so let's keep our energy up until the end!
張り切ろう！
Let me give it our all!
でもさっきからライブの話してるけど みんなライブのタイトル知ってる？
We've been talking about the concert, but does everyone know its title?
今回のライブは題して 「Chromatic Future」！
This concert is titled "Chromatic Future"!
意味わかる人？手を挙げて！
Anyone know what it means? Raise your hand!
こぼが絶対知ってるね
Kobo definitely knows!
そうですね、一番背が高い人が説明するっす！
That's right! The tallest person will explain it!
そう来るかい！まあいいか
Is that how it is?! Oh well.
初めての人も聞いてね
If you're hearing this for the first time, listen up!
「Chromatic Future」ってのは カラフルな未来ってことだよ！
"Chromatic Future" means a colorful future!
ホロライブインドネシアは もう5周年になるからね
Because Hololive Indonesia is reaching its 5th anniversary soon.
私たちはみんなデビューから今日まで 一緒に歩んできたわけ！
All of us have walked together from our debut until today!
それでこれから先も、私たちがカラフルな 時間と思い出を創り出せたらいいなってこと
And moving forward, we hope to create colorful times and memories together...
もちろんホロライブインドネシアのファンとも一緒に！
Of course, together with all the Hololive Indonesia fans!
そうっすよ、カエラ・コヴァルスキア！メモってね！
That's right, Kaela Kovalskia! Take notes!
そうそうそう
Exactly, exactly!
さて、皆さんもうわかりましたよね？ さっきカエラが説明したから
Now then, everyone understands now, right? Since Kaela just explained it.
ってことでライブも始まってることだし
So since the concert has already begun...
本日のライブのことをSNSに投稿する際は
When posting about today's concert on social media...
ハッシュタグ #holoIDChromaticFuture を 忘れずに付けてくださいわ！
Don't forget to include the hashtag #holoIDChromaticFuture!
だってみんなのその…なんていうの、えっと… 情熱！が見たいから！
Because we really want to see everyone's... what do you call it... um... passion!
そうっす！そうっすね！
That's right! Absolutely!
打ち間違えないでね！
Don't make any typos!
いぇー！絶対投稿してね！
Yay! Be sure to post it!
でも正直に言って
But honestly speaking...
「インドネシアライブやるんだよ！」って 言われた時びっくりした？
Were you surprised when told, "We're holding a live concert in Indonesia!"?
もしもし？聞いてくれる？
Hello? Are you listening?
そうっすね！
That's right!
そうっす！あたしも同感！ 妹のゼータに共感しているっす
Exactly! I feel the same way! I totally sympathize with my younger sister Zeta.
そうね、共感ね
Right, sympathy.
カエラ・コヴァルスキアはどう？
How about Kaela Kovalskia?
私もびっくりしたよ なんかこう「え？マジで？」って感じ
I was surprised too. I was like, "Huh? Really?"
なんかこう「え！ついにインドネシアで9人そろって ライブできるんだ！」って！マジかっこいいよね！
Like, "Whoa, all 9 of us can finally perform together in Indonesia!" It's so cool!
かっこいいっす！
It's awesome!
はい、これが初めてホロライブ インドネシアの9人全員でのライブだから
Yes, because this is the first concert featuring all 9 members of Hololive Indonesia...
実はこれはホロライブインドネシアのファンに とても重要な瞬間でもあるんだけど
Actually, this is a very important moment for Hololive Indonesia fans as well...
世界中のみんなも見にきてくれるんでしょう？
Everyone around the world will watch too, right?
さあ答えて
Come on, answer!
はいはい！みんなありがとう！
Yes, yes! Thank you, everyone!
でももちろんこれで終わりって わけじゃないよね？
But of course, this isn't where it ends, right?
だから次はこう…世界征服ってのはどう？
So next... how about world domination?
我々はレディー！レディー！
We are ready! Ready!
レディーレディー！
Ready, ready!
そうっすよカエラ！ゼータ！
That's right, Kaela! Zeta!
この機会におけるファンの支援に加えて
In addition to the fan support on this occasion...
このライブを実現させるために支援をいただいた スポンサーの皆様にも感謝を申し上げまーす！
We would also like to express our gratitude to all the sponsors who supported us in making this live concert possible!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうっす！
みんなありがとうね！
Thank you, everyone!
サンキューサンキュー！
Thank you, thank you!
ところでこのライブって 何か違うところあるのかな？
By the way, is there something different about this live performance?
カエラ気づいた？ 一番気が利くから
Did you notice, Kaela? Since you're the most attentive.
もちろんだよ こぼは気づかないと思うけど
Of course. Though I don't think Kobo noticed.
これだよ 私たちの身体いつもとちょっと違うんだよ
It's this! Our bodies are a little different from usual.
かわいい！クルクル！
So cute! Spin around!
かわいいかわいい！
Cute, cute!
カメラこっち！こっち向けて！こっちこっち！
Camera over here! Point it here! Over here, over here!
始まったなあこれ
Here she goes again...
ほらほら！こぼのかわいさを見て！
Look, look! Look at Kobo's cuteness!
これこれ、お尻
Look at this, my butt!
おいおいおい こぼがカメラ全部乗っ取ってるジャン
Hey, hey, hey! Kobo is taking over all the cameras!
こっちにも向けてよ こぼだけは向けないで
Point it over here too! Don't just point it at Kobo!
いち、にー、さーん… はい終わり！こぼの番っす！
One, two, three... Okay, done! Now it's Kobo's turn!
ストップストップ！やめてって！
Stop, stop! Cut it out!
はいよ ゼータが怒ると怖いからね
Right, because it's scary when Zeta gets angry.
こわいよー
Scary~
もういいや ゼータがカメラを独り占めにしちゃダメっていうのなら... うーん、しょうがない
Fine then. If Zeta says we shouldn't hog the camera... Hmm, oh well.
ファンの皆と遊ぼう！
Let's play with all the fans!
さっきみんなからも大きな声をもらったわけだし 今度はこぼがみんなに大きな声を出したいっす！
Since everyone cheered loudly for us earlier, this time Kobo wants to cheer for everyone!
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes!
そう！みんなにじゃなく、みんなとね
Right! Not at everyone, but with everyone!
そうそう！そういうことっす！
Yeah, yeah! That's what I mean!
だってこれから歌わなきゃいけないから まず声を温存しなきゃでしょ？
Because we have to sing after this, so we should save our voices first, right?
そうっすよ、そんなにカエラの配信時間ほど長くはならないから安心して
That's right, it won't be as long as Kaela's stream time, so don't worry.
まあいい 大声出していいから好きにして
Well, whatever. You can shout all you want, do as you like.
みんな準備はいいかな？
Is everyone ready?
いいかな？
Ready?
もう出来てるみたいっすね！ じゃあこぼから！
Looks like everyone's ready! Then starting with Kobo!
一緒に「BOKOBOKOBO！」って叫ぼう！よしいくよ！
Let's shout "BOKOBOKOBO!" together! Alright, here we go!
いち、に、さん！
One, two, three!
BOKOBOKOBO！
BOKOBOKOBO!
いいわいいね！ 次はゼータ！
Nice, nice! Next is Zeta!
はいはいはい！
Alright, alright!
「ミッションスタート！」って言ったら 一緒に「スタート！」って言ってわ！
When I say "Mission Start!", say "Start!" together with me!
いいか？ アアア！ミッション...
Got it? Ahhh! Mission...
スタート！
Start!
次はカエラ！
Next is Kaela!
よしよし！きてみんな そしてholoh3roも
Alright, alright! Come on everyone, and holoh3ro too!
「holoh3ro！」って言ったら「HU-HA！」で返してね！簡単でしょう？
When I say "holoh3ro!", reply with "HU-HA!". Simple, right?
さあさあさあさあ！
Come on, come on!
準備はいい？ holoh3ro！
Are you ready? holoh3ro!
HU-HA！
HU-HA!
いいわいいね！
Nice, nice!
いいわついに3期生は息ぴったり
Awesome, the 3rd gen is finally in perfect sync!
そうわ まだまだ元気がありそうだね
Yeah, everyone still seems full of energy!
だって、今日の一曲目だけ でももうすごく伝わってくるんだもん
Because even from just our first song today, we could really feel it!
みんなまきがわたしたちの一曲目が 「100%」だなんて思ってた？
Did anyone expect our first song to be "100%"?
思うわけないよな 私もびっくりした
No way anyone expected that! Even I was surprised.
ホシノヴァ気分でライブ開始だなんて！ すごいよね？
Starting the live in Hoshinova mood! Isn't that amazing?
かっこいいっすね、しかもさっきゼータとかが歌った... いや違う
So cool! And earlier when Zeta and... no, wait.
ゼータとカエラが歌った時は もう本家の「100%」みたいっす
When Zeta and Kaela sang, it felt like the original "100%"!
マジかっこよすぎるんだけど なんか、うーぅ！ってなってき！
It was so cool, I was like, "Ooh!"
あんなかっこいい歌を歌ったことあるのかな？
I wonder if you've ever sung such a cool song before?
かっこつけてんの？
Are you showing off?
本物のかっこつけ だってムーナの曲かっこいいもん
The real deal! Because Moona's song is just so cool.
だってゼータがいつもスタイリッシュ とかジャズっぽい曲ばっかっしょ？
Because Zeta usually sings stylish or jazzy songs, right?
だからさっき「100%」を歌った時 めっちゃ雰囲気が違う
So when she sang "100%" earlier, the vibe was totally different!
しかもカエラのラップも！
And Kaela's rap too!
なんかこう...
It was like...
とにかくかっこよかった！すごくわ！
Anyway, it was so cool! Seriously!
でも、それだけじゃないよ！
But that's not all!
次の曲が「NEW zomBIE!!」でした！
The next song was "NEW zomBIE!!"!
これだれの曲わかるよね？
You all know whose song this is, right?
もちろんだよ うちの先輩だ
Of course! It's our senpai's!
holoroのパフォーマンスもめっちゃカッコよかったよ まるでゲームの中にいるみたいだった
holoro's performance was super cool too! It felt like being inside a game.
そうっすわ！ しかもバックダンサーもいたし
That's right! Plus there were back dancers too!
かっこよかったっすね！
It was so cool!
他になんかあったかな？ レーサーも花火も！あと...
What else was there? Lasers, fireworks! And...
すごいギミックがたくさんあったっすね！
There were so many awesome stage gimmicks!
あのバックダンサーたち あたしのソロライブに雇うっす
I'm hiring those back dancers for my solo live!
おっと、もうソロライブの話？
Whoa, talking about a solo live already?
まあ言葉も祈りってやつ
Well, words are like prayers.
でもこのライブまだ終わらないよ！ まだまだ！
But this live performance isn't over yet! Not even close!
でも...さっき何の歌を歌ったか知ってる？
But... do you know what song was sung earlier?
もちろんだよ 私の新しい曲だから
Of course, since it's my new song!
そうっすね まあいいや
Right. Oh well, whatever.
いやいや！タイトルは「dahlah.」だよ！ 「dahlah.」！
No, no! The title is "dahlah."! "dahlah."!
おおなるほど
Oh, I see!
「dahlah.」だったか... まぁわしとだったけど「dahlah.」だったか、 先に言ってよ！
It was "dahlah."... You should've told us beforehand!
だっていつもそれ言ってるじゃん 本当にまあいいやって思ってた
Because you always say that! I thought you really meant "whatever".
それ言って帰ると思ってた
I thought you were going home after saying that.
いやいや、かわいそうだから
No way, that's too sad.
じゃあ「dahlah」ってどういう意味？
Then what does "dahlah" mean?
人生しょうがないって意味
It means "that's life".
人生は重いからまあいいやって言えばいいだけ
Life is heavy, so you just say "whatever".
その後人生を続けようって意味
It means carrying on with life after that.
そうっすね、大人になったらね
That's right, once you become an adult.
幸い曲はリラックスした雰囲気で聴きやすいからファンに挨拶しながらあちこち回れるよね？
Fortunately, the song has a relaxed vibe and is easy to listen to, so we can walk around greeting the fans, right?
楽しかったっすね？サビのダンスもよかった！
That was so fun, wasn't it? The dance during the chorus was great, too!
それ、違う歌じゃない？
Wait, isn't that a different song?
そんなんじゃないと思うけど
I don't think it's like that.
まあ、とにかくこういうリラックスした曲で歌うのは楽しいよね
Well, anyway, singing to a relaxed song like this is really fun.
そうね、リラックス…
Yeah, relaxed...
でもリラックスの話だけどまだリラックスできないんだよ！リラックス！
Speaking of relaxing, we actually can't relax just yet! Calm down!
リラックスしちゃダメって言ったじゃん！
I told you we shouldn't relax yet!
そうそう！あまりにもリラックスしすぎ！
Exactly! You're relaxing way too much!
だってまだまだライブは続くから！
Because the live performance is still going on!
その前にみんななんか一言ある？
Before that, does everyone have something to say?
こっちのおしゃべりさんから！
Starting from this chatty one over here!
三言だけ、「アイ」「ラブ」「ユー」
Just three words: "I," "love," "you."
いいね最高！はっきり言うね！
Awesome, the best! Very clear!
頑張って生きていってね それだけ とにかくいまは人生まだ長いんだから 頑張って！
Keep living strong, that's all. Anyway, life is still long, so do your best!
サランヘヨ！ゴマウォヨ！
I love you! Thank you!
まあ、いつも気楽に元気でいこう！人生あまり真剣に考えすぎないで
Well, let me see... Always stay cheerful and relaxed! Don't take life too seriously!
気楽にね
Just take it easy.
よし、それじゃあ続けようか
Alright, then shall we continue?
おいおい、ちょっと待って！続ける前にファンのみんなと一緒に大声出してみない？
Hey, wait a second! Before continuing, why don't we shout out together with all the fans?
そうっすね！ほら！
That's right! Come on!
よし！じゃあ〜
Alright! Well then~
いちにさんで「Chromatic Future」って大声出してね！
On three, let me hear you shout "Chromatic Future" out loud!
「Chromatic Future！」って感じ？ そうそう！そんな感じ！
Like "Chromatic Future!"? Yeah! Exactly like that!
よし！こほはこっち見て！
Alright! Kobo, look over here!
あたしはこちらにするっす！みんな！
I'll take this side! Everyone!
はいはい！それじゃあこっちはセンターね
Okay! Then I'll take the center!
やほ〜
Yoo-hoo~
じゃあ一緒に…1、2、3！
Then together... 1, 2, 3!
「Chromatic Future」！
"Chromatic Future!"
Everything was easy, I did it all alone
So effortlessly
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold, got all problems solved without any setbacks there is nothing uncontrolled
But there's no way I can begin, dream life that I need to win, I need to feel how all these things crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta soar a little higher, hope all turns to be the things I desire
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap, 'kan 'ku taklukkan gelap, dengan sihir angin 'kan 'ku ajak semua yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit melawan dunia
Like a winged peacock, I will conquer the dark, with the wind's magic I will invite everyone who is asleep to rise up against the world
We'll never give up! As long as we got the strength in ourselves, we could rise above the pain (we're stronger than them)
Walking step by step, trusting my own pace, giving me what I deserve to have (let's go, just believe me)
Let it go, they'll never bring me down, just believe me
Let it go, it'll never bring us down, just believe me
Won't let their cruelty steal in' my royalty, and when the universe works against me I will just
Let it go (If it's spicy, just sip some tea, let it go)
Let it go
I've been living carefree, there's no bitter words in the world that could affect me
I spread my wings and let my magic unfold, not letting it show, stings but I'm bigger than my feelings so that'll be enough
There is no way I can begin, dream life that I need to win, I need to feel how all these things crumble into little pieces
I know I gotta be better than ever, hope all turns to be sweeter than ever
Layaknya burung merak yang bersayap, 'kan 'ku taklukkan gelap, dengan sihir angin 'kan 'ku ajak semua yang terlelap 'tuk bangkit
Like a winged peacock, I will conquer the dark, with the wind's magic I will invite everyone who is asleep to rise up
Melawan dunia
Defying the world
We'll never give up!
As long as we got the strength in ourselves
We could rise above the pain
We're stronger than them!
Walking step by step
Trusting by your pace
Giving me what I deserve to have
Let's go!
Believe me, let it go
They'll never bring me down, just believe me
Let it go
It'll never bring us down, just believe me
Won't let their cruelty
Steal in my royalty
And when the universe moves against me, I will just...
Let it go!
Come on, guys, now let's do this!
One, two, three, let it go!